<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors | ESOP</title>
    <link>http://protist.online/authors/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://protist.online/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Authors</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>http://protist.online/images/logo_hu7dd777bcb87329827d80b28ac3a35910_2007278_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>Authors</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/authors/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Javier del Campo is a Catalan microbial ecologists and Assistant Professor at the Rosenstiel School of Marine and Atmospheric Science at the University of Miami. He completed hi Bachelors and his PhD in Environmental Microbiology and Biotechnology at the University of Barcelona, followed by postdoctoral research at the Institute for Evolutionary Biology (Barcelona), the University of British Columbia (Vancouver) and the Institute of Marine Science (Barcelona). He joined the Marine Ecology and Biology Department at the University of Miami in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adriana Lopes dos Santos</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/adriana-lopes-dos-santos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/adriana-lopes-dos-santos/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Akinori Yabuki</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/akinori-yabuki/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/akinori-yabuki/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alexandra Worden</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/alexandra-worden/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/alexandra-worden/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a microbial ecologist who applies evolutionary biological approaches to understanding diversity and interactions in the ocean. My lab also develops and implements new technologies for targeting wild aquatic microbial populations and individual cells – for both genomic and activity measurements. Of course, since many marine microbes are not yet in culture we have also developed a couple key models in the lab – of environmentally relevant marine algae – so that we can develop cell biological understanding of how these organisms acclimate and adapt to changing environmental conditions on short and long timescales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connecting individual eukaryotic cells with partners in the sea&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know by now that protists are incredibly diverse. But what does this mean in terms of metabolisms and interactions in the sea? This is a difficult question to answer because it is difficult to capture the three dimensional world of a protist at a visualization scale that addresses either of these topics. We employ stable isotope probing and single-eukaryotic-cell sorting to understand who is interacting with whom and the nature of the interaction. These approaches are uncovering the microbiomes of protists and a suite of interactions with associated shifts in metabolism that are not yet represented in typical food web models. Here, we will discuss new discoveries and methodologies for elucidating the mechanistic underpinnings of marine microbial interactions.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andres Gutierrez</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/andres-gutierrez/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/andres-gutierrez/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anna M. G. Novák Vanclová</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/anna-m.-g.-novak-vanclova/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/anna-m.-g.-novak-vanclova/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antonia Cristi</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/antonia-cristi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/antonia-cristi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ben Larson</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/ben-larson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/ben-larson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use microscopes, math, and computation to understand how cells control shape and movement to thrive in various environments. During my undergraduate degree in physics at Reed College, I became increasingly interested in biology and biophysics. After a stint at the National Institutes of Health in a cell biology lab doing a lot of computational image analysis, I joined the Biophysics PhD Program at UC Berkeley. There, I worked in Nicole King&amp;rsquo;s lab on the evolution of multicellular morphogenesis by studying the cellular and biophysical mechanisms regulating 3D colony shape in choanoflagellates. In my postdoc in Wallace Marshall&amp;rsquo;s lab at UCSF, I am investigating the biophysical and computational principles by which cells control complex behaviors through studying locomotion and sensorimotor activity in ciliates and amoebae.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regulation of form in multicellular choanoflagellates and the evolutionary cell biology of morphogenesis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choanoflagellates, the closest living relatives of animals, can form multicellular colonies of various shapes and sizes. This diversity and the simplicity of multicellular forms in conjunction with their important phylogenetic position makes choanoflagellates an ideal system for studying the evolution of morphogenesis. Comparisons between the biology of choanoflagellates and animals has begun to shed light on animal origins. However, because most work has focused on genetics and genomics, little is known about the cellular and biophysical mechanisms underlying the regulation of multicellular form in choanoflagellates. Through the quantitative characterization of the biophysical processes underlying the development of rosette colonies in the choanoflagellate &lt;em&gt;Salpingoeca rosetta&lt;/em&gt;, coupled with perturbative experiments and simulations, we found that that the basal extracellular matrix (ECM) secreted during rosette development exerts a physical constraint on the packing of proliferating cells, thereby sculpting morphogenesis. In addition, simulations yielded a morphospace for the shapes of multicellular colonies, consistent with observations across a range of choanoflagellates. Overall, our biophysical perspective complements previous genetic perspectives and thus helps illuminate the interplay between cell biology and physics in regulating morphogenesis. Another choanoflagellate, the recently discovered &lt;em&gt;Choanoeca flexa&lt;/em&gt;, forms multicellular cup-shaped colonies. Colonies rapidly invert their curvature in response to changing light levels, which they detect through a rhodopsin-cGMP pathway. Inversion is mediated by cell shape changes requiring actomyosin-mediated apical contractility and allows alternation between feeding and swimming behavior. &lt;em&gt;C. flexa&lt;/em&gt; thus rapidly converts sensory inputs directly into multicellular contractions. In this respect, it may inform reconstructions of hypothesized animal ancestors that existed before the evolution of specialized sensory and contractile cells.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charmaine C. M. Yung</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/charmaine-c.-m.-yung/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/charmaine-c.-m.-yung/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daniel Vaulot</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/daniel-vaulot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/daniel-vaulot/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drahomíra Faktorová</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/drahomira-faktorova/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/drahomira-faktorova/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elizabeth Ostrowski</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/elizabeth-ostrowski/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/elizabeth-ostrowski/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fabien Burki</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/fabien-burki/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/fabien-burki/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fabien Burki is an Associate Professor at Uppsala University, Sweden, where he established his research group in 2016 in the Systematic Biology program (Dept. of Organismal Biology). Prior to his move to Sweden, he completed his PhD at the University of Geneva (Switzerland) and a postdoc fellow at the University of British Columbia (Canada). His research focuses on the study of unicellular eukaryotes (aka the protists) from a genomic perspective, in order to understand the great diversity of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filip Husnik</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/filip-husnik/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/filip-husnik/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geoff McFadden</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/geoff-mcfadden/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/geoff-mcfadden/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyeon Been Lee</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/hyeon-been-lee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/hyeon-been-lee/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iñaki Ruiz-Trillo</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/inaki-ruiz-trillo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/inaki-ruiz-trillo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iñaki Ruiz-Trillo is an ICREA Research Professor at the Institut de Biologia Evolutiva (CSIC-UPF) in Barcelona. His current research interests include the origin of multicellular animals, the evolution of eukaryotes and complex life forms, and the understanding of eukaryotic diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The origin of multicellular animals from their perspective of their unicellular relatives&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How animals emerged from their unicellular ancestors remains a mystery. To address this question, we first obtained genome data from the closest unicellular relatives of animals. Comparative genomic analyses demonstrated that the unicellular ancestor of animals was relatively quite complex, with genes involved in cell-adhesion, cell communication and cell differentiation. Moreover, we showed as well that many animal-like features of genomic regulation and spatial cell differentiation were also present in the unicellular ancestor. How those processes were co-opted and expanded, and how different cell types evolved remains unclear, and is the core of our current work.  Overall, all the data generated from the closest unicellular relatives of animals allow us to challenge previous views of animal origins and propose a new perspective on how animals evolved.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Javier del Campo</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/javier-del-campo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/javier-del-campo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Javier del Campo is a Catalan microbial ecologists and Assistant Professor at the Rosenstiel School of Marine and Atmospheric Science at the University of Miami. He completed hi Bachelors and his PhD in Environmental Microbiology and Biotechnology at the University of Barcelona, followed by postdoctoral research at the Institute for Evolutionary Biology (Barcelona), the University of British Columbia (Vancouver) and the Institute of Marine Science (Barcelona). He joined the Marine Ecology and Biology Department at the University of Miami in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Julius Lukeš</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/julius-lukes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/julius-lukes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;A comprehensive view of the euglenozoan mitochondrion&lt;/strong&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Karl Safi</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/karl-safi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/karl-safi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kevin Wakeman</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/kevin-wakeman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/kevin-wakeman/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laura Eme</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/laura-eme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/laura-eme/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mahwash Jamy</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/mahwash-jamy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/mahwash-jamy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Margaret Brisbin</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/margaret-brisbin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/margaret-brisbin/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mariana Câmara dos Reis</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/mariana-camara-dos-reis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/mariana-camara-dos-reis/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark van der Giezen</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/mark-van-der-giezen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/mark-van-der-giezen/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Megan Sørensen</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/megan-s%C3%B8rensen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/megan-s%C3%B8rensen/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miguel Frada</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/miguel-frada/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/miguel-frada/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patrick Keeling</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/patrick-keeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/patrick-keeling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patrick Keeling is a Canadian evolutionary microbiologist and Professor in Botany at the University of British Columbia. He grew up in rural Ontario, and completed a Bachelors at the University of Western Ontario in Genetics and a PhD in Biochemistry at Dalhousie, followed by postdoctoral research at the University of Melbourne and Indiana University. He began his current position as a professor at UBC in Vancouver in 1999.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purificación López-García</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/purificacion-lopez-garcia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/purificacion-lopez-garcia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a biologist interested in very broad questions about the origin and early evolution of life on Earth, with a special focus on microbial lineages, which cover the vast majority of biological diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;The protistan way to fungi&lt;/strong&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raúl González-Pech</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/raul-gonzalez-pech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/raul-gonzalez-pech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Can symbiosis drive genome evolution of Symbiodiniaceae?&lt;/strong&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ross Waller</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/ross-waller/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/ross-waller/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Completed a PhD the University of Melbourne with postdocs at both Melbourne and the University of British Columbia. Returned to a faculty position at the University of Melbourne (2005) and then relocated his lab to the University of Cambridge in 2014. His lab is studying key evolutionary processes and transitions that have led to cell diversity, with particular focus on adaptations for symbiotic interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A subcellular atlas of Toxoplasma reveals the functional and evolutionary context of the proteome&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apicomplexans are human and animal protozoan pathogens responsible for diseases including malaria, cryptosporidiosis and toxoplasmosis. As obligate intracellular parasites they are highly organised cells with numerous novel and specialised sub-compartments that form the basis of their invasion biology, host defence evasion, and novel metabolic traits. However, our understanding of these cells is highly constrained by our limited knowledge of the locations and functions of most of the cell’s proteome. Even in the best-studied apicomplexans (Plasmodium and Toxoplasma) only a small fraction of proteins’ locations has been experimentally determined, with most assignments based on predictions from orthologues in distant relatives. Moreover, many parasite proteins are annotated as ‘hypotheticals’, for example 4113 of 8121 Toxoplasma proteins, and many are unique to parasites stymying even predictions of location or function by comparative biology. To address this deficit in our basic understanding of the compositional organisation of the apicomplexan cell, we have used a spatial proteomics method called hyperLOPIT to simultaneously capture the steady-state subcellular association of thousands of proteins in the apicomplexan Toxoplasma. These protein atlases reveal: the landscapes of conservation and novelty of cell compartments through evolutionary time; contemporary differences of selective pressures across the different cell compartments; clear instances of protein relocation from one organelle to a different one during apicomplexan speciation; and presence of cell structures otherwise thought lost. This new, global view of the organisation of the apicomplexan cell proteome provides a much more complete framework for understanding the mechanisms of function, evolution and biology of these cells.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruth S. Eriksen</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/ruth-s.-eriksen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/ruth-s.-eriksen/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Susannah Porter</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/susannah-porter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/susannah-porter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Susannah received her bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Mathematics from Yale University in 1995 and her Ph.D. in Biology at Harvard University in 2002. After completing a one-year NASA Astrobiology Post-Doctoral Fellowship at UCLA, she moved to the University of California at Santa Barbara, where she is Professor and Vice Chair in the Department of Earth Science. She studies the fossil record of early eukaryotes and early animals, and has worked on problems relating to the evolution of skeletal biomineralization, the influence of snowball Earth glaciations on the biosphere, and the taxonomy and ecology of ancient protistan microfossils.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Insights into eukaryogenesis from the fossil record&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eukaryogenesis—the process by which the eukaryotic cell emerged—has long puzzled scientists. It has been assumed that the fossil record has little to say about this process, in part because important characters such as the nucleus and mitochondria are rarely preserved, and in part because the prevailing model of early eukaryotes implies that eukaryogenesis occurred before the appearance of the first eukaryotes recognized in the fossil record. I propose a different scenario for early eukaryote evolution than what is widely assumed. Rather than crown group eukaryotes originating in the late Paleoproterozoic (~1.7 billion years ago; Ga) and remaining ecologically minor components for more than half a billion years in a prokaryote-dominated world, I argue for a late Mesoproterozoic origin of the eukaryotic crown group (~1.1 Ga), implying that eukaryogenesis can be studied using the fossil record. I review the proxy records of four crown group characters: the capacity to form cysts (as evidenced by the presence of excystment structures); a complex cytoskeleton (as evidenced by spines or pylomes); sterol synthesis (as evidenced by steranes); and aerobic respiration—and therefore mitochondria—(as evidenced by eukaryotes living in oxic environments), and argue that it might be possible to use these proxy records to infer the order in which these characters evolved. The records indicate that both cyst formation and a complex cytoskeleton appeared by late Paleoproterozoic time (&amp;gt;1.6 Ga), and sterol synthesis appeared in the late Mesoproterozioc or early Neoproterozoic (1.1–0.8 Ga). The origin of aerobic respiration cannot as easily be pinned down, but current evidence permits the possibility that it evolved as late as 1.1 Ga.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tristan Biard</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/tristan-biard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/tristan-biard/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Varsha Mathur</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/varsha-mathur/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/varsha-mathur/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a PhD student in [Patrick Keeling&amp;rsquo;s lab]. I&amp;rsquo;m studying the evolution of parasitism in apicomplexans using single-cell transcriptomics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plastid evolution in deep-branching apicomplexans&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apicomplexans are a group of obligate animal parasites that include devastating pathogens such as Plasmodium, the causative agent of malaria. One of the most fascinating traits of these parasites is that they retain a relic, non-photosynthetic plastid (known as the apicoplast). This organelle sheds light on the evolutionary history of the apicomplexans, but also serves as an important tool to explore principles of organelle dependency and genome reduction, more generally. Here, we carried out genome and transcriptome sequencing of three under-studied apicomplexan species, &lt;em&gt;Aggregata octopiana&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Merocystis kathae&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Margolisiella islandica&lt;/em&gt;. We use multi-gene phylogenomics to place these taxa into a novel deep-branching apicomplexan clade and sequence their apicoplast genomes. We find that plastids in deep-branching apicomplexans are highly reduced, encode only a handful of proteins, and contain some of the most AT-rich genomes ever found. The plastid of &lt;em&gt;Margolisiella islandica&lt;/em&gt; is particularly remarkable as it is the smallest apicoplast genome sequenced till date and has lost all plastid-encoded RNA polymerase genes.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yana Eglit</title>
      <link>http://protist.online/author/yana-eglit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://protist.online/author/yana-eglit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PhD Candidate at the lab of Alastair Simpson; we study the diversity and evolution of free-living, heterotrophic protists from a variety of environments, currently focusing on marine benthos and high salt environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meteora, “Protist X”, and what we can learn from culturing the diversity of eukaryotes&lt;/strong&gt;
Yana Eglit, Takashi Shiratori, Jon Jerlstöm-Hultqvist, Andrew J. Roger, Ken-Ichiro Ishida, Alastair G.B. Simpson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To a first approximation, eukaryote diversity is comprised of protists. After three centuries of exploring microscopic life, we are still finding protists that are dramatically different from any known forms, and often distantly related to well-studied eukaryotes. Here, we present two examples of newly cultivated organisms, whose place in the eukaryote tree of life was completely unclear from morphology. &lt;em&gt;Meteora sporadica&lt;/em&gt; was described in 2002, but there were neither cultures nor molecular data available. It has a strikingly unusual cell organisation unlike either a ‘flagellate’ or an ‘amoeba’: the central cell body bears long thin anterior and posterior extensions (the ‘long axis’), plus (usually) two shorter lateral ‘arms’, which swing back and forth, collecting bacteria as the cell glides on its long axis. ‘Protist X’, an undescribed organism, is a protist-eating anaerobe with four flagella in a cruciform arrangement. Phylogenies constructed from &amp;gt;200 genes show, surprisingly, that both Meteora and ‘Protist X’ are placed outside any established “kingdom” or “supergroup” of eukaryotes, demonstrating how there are not only novel species still to discover, but entire new major groups of previously uncharacterised eukaryotes. Great strides have recently been made in uncovering this diversity with environmental molecular methods (including single cell genomics/transcriptomics and metagenomics), yet classical culturing approaches continue to yield a greater proportion of significant novel lineage discoveries, and remain crucially important for revealing the planet’s microbial biodiversity.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
